Josiah Manning

Portland, OR

Cell: 562-298-7901

Email: josiah.t.manning@biola.edu

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/josiah-manning/

Portfolio: https://jtvanilla1.github.io/ **GitHub:** https://github.com/jtvanilla1

Professional Summary

I am a full-stack Scrum engineer from Portland, OR with a wide variety of experience and familiarities. I pride myself on versatility, adaptability, and communication. I am highly motivated by the values of Scrum, and I am passionate about user experience.

I graduated from Biola University with a B.S. in Computer Science, and took a mobile developer internship in Portland, which sadly was cancelled due to COVID-19. Since then, I have been building web projects and Python scripts on LeetCode to hone my skills. My long-term goal is to be a project leader or manager of a small team designing products and solutions, preferably in aerospace engineering, military contracting, or entertainment industries.

Relevant Technologies and Skills

Languages:

Python, C++, Java, Dart with Flutter, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, Bootstrap 3 and 4, some React

Programs:

Visual Studio, NetBeans, GitHub, MS Office Suite, Anaconda, Access, Android Studio

Concepts:

Agile Methodologies, Scrum, relational database schemas and implementation, mobile apps, web development, RESTful APIs

Education

Biola University, Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, 2013-2019 Pursuing PSM I

Relevant Work Experience

Miller Paint Company, Sales Engineer II, Portland OR

June 2020 – Current

- Data entry and QA for order processing, tinting, and mixing, with excellent attention to detail.
- Troubleshooting and maintenance of hardware and software
- Performed accounting requirements for customer purchasing and account history.
- Followed inventory policies and procedures for merchandising and receiving.
- Consulted customers with proper techniques and products based on their goals and requirements.

PandaSoft, Mobile Developer Intern Portland OR

April 2020 to June 2020

- Developed Android and iOS apps using Flutter.
- Designed an Android movie trailer app that streams current and popular movie data through TMDB API and YouTube, following Scrum methodologies.
- Researched relevant market details for effective design strategies and next-generation markets.